我11点就得到俱乐部  所以我没时间多说
I need to be at the club by 11:00, so I can't really talk.
不去
Uh skip it?
但重要的人都会去的
But everyone who's anyone is gonna be there.
我知道
Mm. I know.
我真的得挂了
Look, I really got to go.
我会想你的
But I'll be thinking about you.
我会照张照片发你证明我想你
I'll take a pic and send it to you to prove it.
有人吗
Hello?
谁啊
Is someone there?
很好  哼哼
Excellent. Now hum.
振动嘴唇
Vibrate, vibrate, vibrate, vibrate.
-好了  呼吸  -行了  我觉得
- Okay. Now, breathing... - Okay, no, I think...
我觉得我的声带
I think that's... my vocal cords
已经准备得够可以的了
are about as warmed up as they're gonna get.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
你不是说你只是来旁观的吗
I thought you said you were just coming to watch, anyway.
本来是这么打算的
Well, that was the plan,
可我发现你需要我的专业帮助
but then I discovered my expertise was needed.
别忘了他的额头  亲爱的
And don't miss his forehead, honey.
太油亮了  这件外衣好吗
It's shiny. What about this jacket, dear?
-你选的...  -嗯  没问题的
- Did you choose... - Yes. I-I'm good. I'm... y--
-我亲自选的  谢谢  -因为
- I picked that out myself, thank you. - Because...
我不是第一次了  妈妈
I've done this before, mother.
我心里有数的
I know exactly what I'm doing.
谢谢  再加上一层吧
Thank you. Go ahead and just put one more.
加一层书
Just another layer.
摞起来
Stack them right up on top of there.
我觉得会很棒的
I think it'll be great.
那边有个人在用手机拍你
There's a boy over there filming you with his phone.
那是什么幕后花絮之类的
Yeah, that just behind-the-scenes stuff.
嗯  都是为了宣传  进入那种
Yeah. It's all part of the campaign. Just tapping into
全方位无死角的数字媒体环境中
that whole 360-degree digital-media environment.
好吧
Uh-huh. Okay.
好了
Okay.
卡塞尔先生  我们好了
Mr. Castle, we're ready.
很好  去跟老莫一起坐下吧
Excellent. Want to go sit with Moe?
-好的  老莫  -太棒了
- Whoo-hoo, Moe. - Perfect.
-开拍了  -好的
- We're rolling. - All right.
开拍
And action!
我是理查德·卡塞尔
I'm Richard Castle.
你想看一本深寒彻骨
Are you looking for a bone-chilling,
令人后背发凉  曲折迷离的小说吗
spine-tingling thriller fullf twists and turns?
如果是的话  那么我的《狂怒希特》就是上选
If you are, look no further than my latest novel, "Raging Heat."
今天就下载一本吧
Why don't you download your copy today?
因为不管你是下载
Because wether you get it on the download,
买纸质书  还是听有声书
buy a hard copy, or just listen to the audio version,
我保证
I promise you,
这本书都会令你沉迷不已
it'll keep you hooked till the very last word.
那一定很尴尬吧
That must have been kind of embarrassing.
的确有点伤到我的自尊
It was a minor blow to my ego.
但之后  我向内心的卡塞尔汲取力量
But after that, I had to channel my inner Castle.
之后  便所向披靡
But once I did, nailed it.
你完美地扮演了自己
Wow, you nailed playing yourself.
真厉害
That's impressive.
随你嘲笑吧
Eh, mock if you will,
但很快  你就会在各种平台上
but pretty soon, you're gonna see my image
看到我的形象了
splashed across multiple platforms.
就像卡塞尔升级版
It's gonna be Castle 2.0.
卡塞尔云端版
It's gonna be Castle in the cloud.
等等  多平台
Wait a minute. Multiple platforms?
不是电视广告吗
I thought that this was a tv commercial.
不  比那更好  是网络广告
No, better... it's a webmercial.
等几天后发行了
And once it drops in a few days,
我的出版商向我保证  我和《狂怒希特》
my publisher assures me that both "Raging Heat" and I
都会大热
will go viral.
我也该允许科技给我一个温暖暴赚的拥抱了
It's time I let technology wrap me in its warm yet lucrative embrace.
先生们早
Gentlemen.
有电梯吗  还是得走上去
Is there an elevator? Is this a walk-up?
希望有电梯
Hope it's an elevator.
被害人名叫艾比·史密斯  23岁
Victim's name is Abby Smith. She's 23 years old.
一名维修人员今早发现了她
A maintenance worker found her early this morning.
这事很不对劲
We're dealing with something messed up here.
没错  首先是这些刺伤
You got that right, starting off with these stab wounds.
是圆形的  凶器是什么
They're round. What was the murder weapon?
不好说
Hard to tell.
编织针  或者冰锥
A knitting needle, maybe, or an ice pick.
我也猜不准
Your guess is as good as mine.
她的袭击者懂解剖
Her attacker knew about anatomy.
他刺穿了她的颈动脉和锁骨下动脉
He pierced her carotid and her subclavian arteries.
她数分钟内流血致死
She bled out in minutes.
那么凶手可能有医学背景
Which means our killer might have had a medical background.
这里没有强行闯入的痕迹
You know, there are no signs of forced entry.
凶手是怎么进来的
Do we know how this killer came in?
不能确定
Well, we're not really sure.
但他绝对想让艾比知道他来了
But he definitely wanted Abby to know that he was here.
这是10:33发给她的照片
She was texted this photo at 10:33,
就在死亡时间附近
right around time of death.
这是凶手发的
The killer sent this?
就在杀害她之前
Right before he murdered her.
他在监视她
He was watching her.
然后又发来照片吓唬她
And then he sent that to terrorize her.
这是私人恩怨
This was personal.
这下科技的拥抱可不温暖了
Well, so much for the warm embrace of technology.
可以追查短信吗
Is there any way to trace the text?
试过了  是一次性手机发来的
Well, we'll try, but it was sent from a burner phone.
同时  我们去问下邻居
Um, meanwhile, we'll check with the neighbors
看他们看见什么没
and see if they saw anything.
记得也问下朋友和家人
Okay, and talk to friends and family.
如果这是私人恩怨
If this was personal,
他们也许会知道与谁有关
they might have an idea as to who was behind this.
我们为何不从他开始
Why don't we start with this guy?
卡洛斯
Carlos.
被害人收到信息前
She was on the phone with him
刚与他通完电话
right before she received the text message.
从通话记录看  他应该是被害者男友
Judging by their call history, he looks to be the boyfriend.
真不敢相信她被杀了
I can't believe this happened.
要是我当时跟她在一起就好了
I should've been there to protect her.
卡洛斯  我们想问下你
We have to ask you, Carlos,
还有谁有艾比家的钥匙
who else had a key to Abby's place?
没有别人
Nobody.
除了房东以外
Just the landlord.
她是在家等什么客人吗
You know if she was expecting any visitors?
没有
No.
她当时正准备去末日俱乐部
She was actually heading out to Club Doom.
她在那儿有个个人见面会
She had booked a personal appearance there.
艾比是名人吗
Uh... Abby was a celebrity?
她在社交网络上很活跃
She was huge on social media.
她是演员  歌手还是别的
So, was she an actress or a singer or what?
不是   她在Snappamatic上面分享照片
No. She posted pics on Snappamatic --
就那个照片分享软件
You know, the photo-sharing app.
她管那叫Snappamatic评论
"Snappamatic reviews," She called them.
上面有她的照片
And that got her personal appearances?
还有赞助商
Yeah, and sponsors, too,
尤其她有五十万粉丝
Especially when she hit half a million followers.
她主要评论些什么
What did Abby review, exactly?
就是段子
They were, like, joke reviews.
她来纽约是为了成为喜剧演员
She came to New York to be a comedian,
这就是
And, um, this...
让她成名的照片
is how she hit it big.
这家希腊烤肉难吃得直接吐出来
"These gyros came right back up.
这种买一送一你可不会想要
That's a two-for-one special you don't want."
这张照片火了
This pic went viral and...
一夜之间  她就成了明星
Overnight, she was a star,
追随者  粉丝  她因此备受关注
With followers and fans, all this attention.
我觉得自己要失去她了
I-I felt like I was losing her.
感觉已经没有两人空间了
Like there was no room left for the two of us.
有人跟踪她吗
Do you think she had any stalkers?
如果有  她也不一定会告诉我
If she did, I'm not sure she would have told me.
有什么被评论的人
Did any of these reviewees
对这些照片表示生气吗
get upset about the pictures she posted?
确实有
Actually, yeah.
有个男的  打过恐吓电话
There was a guy -- he made threatening calls.
他叫什么
What was his name?
爱德华·韩.
Edward Han.
他是个针灸师
He's an acupuncturist.
他的电话记录显示  艾比死前几天内
His cellphone records show that he called Abby
他给她打了数十通电话
a dozen times in the days before her murder.
说起精确扎针杀人  没有人
And who better than an acupuncturist
比针灸师更在行了  说不定凶器就是大针头
to kill with accurate punctures, perhaps with a giant needle?
而且他精通解剖学知道往哪下手
And he has the anatomical training to know where to strike.
更别提艾比还得罪过他
Not to mention beef with Abby.
看看这张图
Check this out.
现在到处都是
This was posted all over the place,
我猜对韩的生意打击很大
And I bet it put a damper on Han's practice.
别让这家伙捅你
"Do not let this guy poke you."
我不明白
I don't get it.
到处上传这种傻B照片
Posting dumb-ass photos all over the place --
她是怎么会有粉丝团的
How did she have a fan base?
这怎么成就一个事业的
How did this become a career?
欢迎来到分享经济时代
Welcome to the sharing economy.
得了  分享过度了
Yeah, more like over-sharing.
真的吗  你反对所有上传裸露照片的女人吗
Really? And you're opposed to all photos of over-sharing women?
那不一样
That's different.
看来韩真有点可疑
Han's starting to look good for this.
艾比的一个邻居昨天看见韩在她公寓出现
One of Abby's neighbors saw him at her apartment yesterday.
在她公寓  他去干嘛
At her apartment? Doing what?
对她大叫  威胁说  会让她付出代价
Screaming at her, threatening to "Make her pay"
直到她砰得关上门
Till she slammed the door in his face.
那么也许他回去表明立场了
So maybe he went back to get the last word.
我根本没回去过
I never went back.
我承认  我是去过她公寓
I admit, I was at her apartment
也的确说过那些狠话
and I may have said those things.
你对这评论很生气
You were angry about this review.
评论
Review?
这婊子都没来消费过
That bimbo was never even a client.
自她上传这张照片  我的生意一落千丈
She posted that picture, and my walk-ins dropped off.
她的无良段子毁了我的生意
Her little joke was costing me my business.
在我们看来  那就是作案动机
Yeah, well, in our business, we call that motive.
昨晚10点30你在哪
Where were you last night at 10:30?
独自悲伤中
Off drowning my sorrows.
我向你发誓  我真没杀她
I swear to you, I did not do this.
但我知道是谁干的
But I know who did.
她有个跟踪者
She had a stalker.
我知道  我们正看着他呢
Yeah, I know. We're looking at him.
不是我  艾比也以为我在跟踪她
Not me. That's what Abby thought, too -- that I was stalking her.
她为什么会这样想呢
Now, why would she think that?
或许是因为你整天打她电话
Maybe because you were calling her all the time,
还去她公寓找她
showing up at her place?
艾比说从上个月开始就有人在跟踪她
Abby said someone had been following her for the last month,
但我是上周才找到她的
But I didn't track her down till a week ago.
所以跟踪狂不可能是我
So the stalker couldn't have been me.
韩先生  你什么证据证明
Mr. Han, do you have evidence
你说的这人真实存在
that this other person actually exists?
明信片上有段话
There's a note on a postcard.
-什么话  -一段恐吓的话
- What note? - A threat.
她死的那天收到的
She got it that day.
她拿出来给我看
She waved it in my face.
说是我偷偷塞进她门里
She accused me of slipping it under her door.
留下那段话的人就是凶手
Whoever left that note -- that's who did this.
一定是
It has to be.
韩的不在场证明查实了
Han's alibi checks out.
酒保说案发时他正在享受他的第四杯鸡尾酒
Bartender said he was well into his fourth mai tai at the time of the murder.
再仔细想想
Upon reflection, it's just as well
从讲故事的立场来说
from a storytelling standpoint.
刚说完"别让这家伙捅你"
I mean, "Do not let this guy poke you,"
然后针灸师就拿着根大针捅死她
then the acupuncturist stabs her with a giant needle.
这有点明显过头了
It's just a little too obvious.
也就是说我们要找另一个有动机的人
Which means we're looking for someone else with motive,
但目前为止  没人浮出来
But so far, no one sticks out.
也许艾比的家人有什么想法
Maybe Abby's family has some insight.
没有  她跟他们不是很亲密
They don't. She wasn't very close to them.
看来韩说的威胁的事是真的
Looks like Han was telling the truth about that threat.
鉴证组在艾比的梳妆台抽屉里找到了这张明信片
CSU Found this postcard in Abby's dresser drawer.
"最亮的星星也是最快逝去的"
"The brightest stars burn quickest."
这是她被杀当天收到的吗
She got this on the same day she was murdered?
等等  这是指纹吗
Wait, is this a fingerprint?
不  只是块污渍  但也许是线索
No. That's a smudge, but it might mean something.
实验室说是木材清漆
The lab says that it's wood varnish.
伙计们  看看这个
Hey, guys. Check this out.
我查了艾比的粉丝
I was looking through Abby's followers,
有个人在自己的账号上发了她的照片
And one of them posted pictures of her on their account.
犯罪现场的照片
Crime-scene photos?
但不是我们的
But not ours.
凶手在我们到达现场前
The killer took these photos
拍下了这些照片
before we got to the crime scene.
"这颗明星的耀眼时刻过去了"
"This star's 15 seconds are over."
这是谁的账号
Whose account is this?
用户名叫"网络杀手"
Username is "Net slayer."
他杀了她  然后晒出了她的照片
He kills her, then posts her picture.
他为什么这么做
Why would he do that?
毁掉被害人形象  再施以侮辱
Well, tear down the victim, add insult to injury.
"这颗明星的耀眼时刻过去了"
"This star's 15 seconds are over."
也许这就是他杀艾比的原因
Maybe that's why he killed Abby,
因为她是网络红人
Because she was a web celebrity.
也可能他自己也想红
Or he wants to become one himself.
艾比可有五十万粉丝
Abby did have half a million followers.
杀了她会让他立马受到关注
Killing her would give him instant high profile.
也可能他只是在利用社交媒体
Or he could just be using social media
来掩盖他真实的作案动机
to hide his true motives for killing her.
不管怎样  也许这些照片能帮我们找到他
Either way, maybe these photos could help us find him.
嗯  我去找托瑞分析一下这些照片
Yeah, I'll get with Tory. We'll analyze the photos,
看能不能从倒影里提取出人像
see if we can pull some images off the reflections.
我再查查他的账号
And I'll go through his account,
看有没有其他内容能帮我们确认他的身份
see if he posted anything else that could help us I.D. Him.
你们去哪
Where you guys going?
直接去源头
Straight to the source...
也许snappamatic能告诉我们
Maybe Snappamatic can give us an idea
他是谁  或者去哪找他
Who he is or where to find him.
其实  确认用户身份和对其定位
Actually, ID'ing and locating users
恰恰是我们不能做的两件事
are two things we just can't do.
不能还是不想
Can't or won't?
不能
Can't.
Snappamatic是基于保护隐私而设计
Snappamatic was designed for privacy.
它运行的软件平台
It runs on a software platform
会将所有用户匿名
that anonymizes all of our users.
这对凶手来说肯定是最满意的一点
I bet that was a real selling point for the killer.
听着  没人比我们更恼火这事了
Look, no one is more upset about this than we are.
艾比·史密斯肯定更恼火
I bet Abby Smith was.
你们的一个用户杀了她
One of your users killed her,
而你们却想告诉我你们帮不上忙
and you're trying to tell me that you can't help us.
我们在尽力  伊万在梳理这家伙的账号
We're trying. Evan's combing the guy's account,
可注册咱们网站只要一个有效的电邮地址就行
but all you need to register is a valid e-mail address.
他的电邮现在已经不可用了  所以毫无帮助
Which isn't valid anymore, by the way, so no help there.
我们只能封掉他的账号  让他不能再发东西
What we can do is suspend his account so he can't post.
好吧  他之所以会发东西
Uh, well, the reason he's posting in the first place
是想获得关注
is because he wants attention.
-他需要交流  -没错
- He needs to communicate. - Exactly.
他喜欢分享  那就让他分享
He likes to share, so let him.
也许他会无意中分享出什么东西
Maybe he's gonna share something that he didn't intend to.
把图片撤下来  但别封他的号
Now, take the pictures down but leave the account up.
我们不希望网站的品牌
W-we'd rather not have the snappamatic brand
跟一个杀人凶手扯上关系
associated with a murderer.
已经扯上了
It already is.
这是我们直通凶手的管道
It's our pipeline directly to the killer.
账号不准封
The account stays open.
往好处想想  先生们
Coider the bright side, gentlemen...
你们网站的浏览量会破表的
The traffic for your site will be through the roof.
我好像有发现了
I think I got something.
我在挖掘元数据
I was digging through the metadata
发现其中一张图片上有异常的地理标签
and found a GeoTag anomaly on one of the pictures.
什么样的异常
What kind of an anomaly?
是这样  地理标签包含了GPS坐标
Okay, so, the GeoTag holds GPS coordinates,
通常也就是照片被拍摄的地点
Usually of where a photo was taken.
通常  但并不一定吗
Usually but not always?
如果相机失去了GPS信号就不行
Not if the camera loses its GPS signal.
这样的话
In that case,
地理标签就会指向照片被上传的地点
A GeoTag is assigned when the photo is uploaded.
所以  凶手没注意到他失去了GPS信号
So, the killer lost his GPS signal, didn't notice...
然后当他上传照片时
and then when he posted his photos onto snappamatic,
就意外地泄漏了他的位置
he accidentally revealed his location.
坐标是什么
Wh-what are the coordinates?
托瑞标出了地理标签的经纬度
Tory plotted the longitude and latitude of the GeoTag,
得到了一个在曼哈顿市区的地址
and we got an address in downtown Manhattan.
是什么地方
And what's there?
是个木制家具店
It's a vintage furniture store.
木...木材清漆
W-w-wood...wood...wood varnish.
这就跟纸上的污渍对上了
That explains the smudge on the note.
好  去拿到那里所有员工的姓名
Okay, let's get the names of everyone that works there.
已经去过了
We already did.
是家个体经营的店  店主叫比尔·加瑞特
It's a one-man shop owned by one Bill Garrett.
他以前是个警察
Turns out he used to be a cop
直到发生精神崩溃
until he had a nervous breakdown.
还有  他在网络部工作
And get this -- he worked in the cyber division.
这就意味着他很懂网络和社交媒体
Which means he would know his way around the web and social media.
带他来问话
Bring him in.
比尔·加瑞特  纽约警局
Bill Garrett. NYPD.
举起手让我们看到
Keep your hands where we can see them.
跪下  你知道流程的
On your knees. You know the drill.
被抓来警局是退休警员应得的待遇吗
Getting brought in here is no way to treat a fellow officer.
加瑞特先生  我们在你的商店里搜到了这些
Mr. Garrett, we found these when we searched your shop.
我是做家具翻修的  我当然有钻头
I re-finish furniture. Of course I have awls.
和她颈上的伤口吻合的钻头吗
Awls that match the stab wounds in her neck?
如果你认为是我杀害了这个女孩
If you think I murdered this girl,
那你一定是疯了
you're out of your mind.
我们还发现了这部手机
We also found this cellphone.
-买来以防万一的  -以防万一
- Keep it for emergencies. - Emergencies?
以防需要拍照吗
Like, uh, snapping photos?
你看  就算你删除了它们
You see, even when you delete them,
还是可以还原的
they can still be recovered.
这是搞什么啊  不是我拍的
All right, what is this? I didn't take those.
那为什么会出现在你的手机里
Then how did they end up on your phone?
而且为什么是从你的无线网
And why were they uploaded to Snappamatic
上传到Snappamatic上的
using your wifi network?
我从来不上传照片
I don't upload photos.
除非必要  我都不上网的
I don't even go near the web unless I have to.
还有发给艾比的信息
And then there's the text to Abby
这张明信片上的木材清漆
and the wood varnish on this note,
只要检查  肯定会发现来自你的商店
which we're gonna trace right back to your shop.
结束了
It's over.
你最好的选择就是认罪签协议
Your best bet is to cut a deal.
你们搞错了
This is a mistake.
在网络部工作肯定对你造成了巨大伤害吧
Working cyber unit must have taken its toll.
你一定很不容易
It had to have been difficult.
亲眼见证着网络的阴暗面
Seeing the darkest side of the web --
肯定对你有所改变吧
that must have changed you.
也许这就是你辞职并干下这种事的原因
Maybe that's why you left and did what you did.
我什么也没干
I didn't do anything.
我辞职是因为一个兄弟会成员约会强暴了一个女孩
And I quit cyber because a frat boy date-raped a girl,
把照片发到了网上  还逍遥法外
posted the photos online, and got away with it,
所以我失控暴怒  打伤了他
so I flipped out and I put him in the hospital.
我没有伤害这个女孩
I did not hurt this girl.
我都不知道她是谁
I do not know her.
你昨晚10点30分左右在哪里
Where were you at 10:30 P.M.?
-在家  -和谁在一起
- I was at home. - With who?
没人
Nobody.
我独居
I was alone.
这刚刚发布在网络杀手的账号上
This was just posted to the Net Slayer's account.
是你们逮捕加瑞特的画面
That's you guys arresting Garrett.
等等  这是什么
Wait, what's this?
抓错人了  纽约警局
"Wrong suspect, NYPD.
我还在
"I'm still here.
接下来我要干什么呢
What will I do next?"
要么是加瑞特被陷害了
So, either Garrett was framed...
要么就是他用什么办法
Or somehow, he pulled this off
制造了自己被陷害的假象
to make it look like he was framed.
不管这人是谁  他把这事提升到了全新的高度
Whoever this is, he just took this to a whole new level.
他在嘲弄我们
He's taunting us.
又有图片发布了
More pictures are coming in.
这是人体吗
Body parts?
人体  香肠  一个日期
Body parts, sausages, a date.
这到底是什么啊
What the hell is this?
游戏开始了
"The game is on."
这是个挑战  那些是线索
That's a challenge. Those are clues.
什么的线索
Clues to what?
下一次谋杀
His next murder.
人体  香肠  11月12号
Body parts, sausage, november 12th.
把人体做成香肠
Body parts being made into sausage.
11月的人肉香肠
Human sausages in november.
完全摸不到头绪
I am not getting anywhere with this.
你确定吗  好的  谢谢
And you're sure? Okay. Thanks.
加瑞特的不在场证明有效
Garrett's alibi checks out.
他昨晚回家后开启了报警系统
He activated his alarm system when he got home last night,
之后直到早上都再无人进出过
and no one entered or exited until morning.
所以凶手陷害了他  就为了耍我们
So the killer set him up just to toy with us.
警探  新闻媒体要求我们做出回应
Detective, the news media's calling for comment.
总局想知道我们的意见
1PP wants to know what we think this is.
现在还不能下定论
We're not sure.
这可能是指向下一个或几个被害人的线索
This could be a clue as to his next victim or victims.
每张图可能都代表不同的人
Each image could represent a different person.
也可能是种图形符号
Or it could be a pictogram,
所有图片合起来能传递某个信息
where the images add up to a message.
托瑞正在分析图像  看能不能查到来源
Tory's trying to analyze each image, find their sources.
但我们认为这组剪贴画
But we think that this collage
来自一张20多岁白人女性的照片
is from one photo of a woman, Caucasian, in her 20s.
那么她可能就是下一个目标
So she could be our next target.
鉴于凶手的行为
And given the killer's behavior,
她很可能是一个网络达人
she's most likely someone with a high internet profile,
就像艾比·史密斯
like Abby Smith.
我们确认那个烤炉是富勒烤架
So, we I.D'd that grill as a Fowler.
我们在查找所有在社交媒体上
We're checking into anybody named Fowler
比较火的名叫富勒的人
who might be big on social media.
日期11月12号  有特殊含义吗
And that date, november 12th -- any special significance?
首先  它是世界肺炎日
Well, for starters, it turns out it is world pneumonia day.
不过我们还在寻找相关的新闻事件
But we're also checking into any news events,
和那天的出生和死亡
births, deaths that occurred on that day.
如果说那真是个日期的话
If it even is a date.
11  12  13可能是个序列
11, 12, 13 could be part of a number sequence.
没错  卡塞尔  我们也调查了这方面
Yes, Castle, we're also looking into that,
还有加瑞特在网络部期间抓到的犯人
as well as anyone Garrett put away while he was in cyber.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett?
我查到了其中一副图像
I was able to identify one of the images.
是这位美食博主玛丽·弗斯的
It was cropped from this photo of a food blogger
一张照片中截取的
named Mary Fuchs.
你从哪找到的这张照片
Where did you find that photo?
她几天前上传到Snappamatic上的
She posted it on her Snappamatic feed a few days ago.
玛丽·弗斯是Snappamatic的用户  和艾比·史密斯一样
So Mary Fuchs is a Snappamatic user, just like Abby Smith.
她可能是下个受害者
She could be next.
我们得找到她  把她带过来
We need to find her and bring her in here.
我不明白
I don't understand.
为什么会有人截取上传我的一张照片
Why would someone post part of my picture?
弗斯女士  这些图片能让你想起什么吗
Ms. Fuchs, do these images mean anything to you?
这个日期呢
Or this date?
不知道
No.
我应该不知道
I mean, I don't think so.
那艾比·史密斯呢  你认识她吗
What about Abby Smith? Do you know her?
你跟她有什么关系吗
Do you have any connection to her?
在她被杀的消息上新闻之前
I-I'd never even heard of her
我都从来没听说过这个人
till it was all over the news that she died.
杀她的凶手也要杀我吗
Is whoever killed her after me?
有人跟踪过你吗
Well, has anyone been following you?
你受到过威胁信件吗
Have you received any threatening messages?
没有  没有那种事
No, nothing like that.
你是博主  对吧
You're a blogger, right?
你的博客是关于什么的
What do you blog about?
德国菜肴
German cuisine.
German cuisine?
我是德国人  所以我给德国餐厅做点评
I'm German, so I review German restaurants,
而且我也发一些经典菜品的食谱  比如果馅卷
and I post recipes for classic dishes like strudel and --
还有图片中我正在烤的小香肠
and the bratwurst that I'm grilling in the picture.
你的Snappamatic主页上显示你有...
So, your Snappamatic page says that you have...
47名粉丝
47 followers?
是的
Yeah.
我上周才加入的  这已经很好了
I think that's pretty good, considering I joined last week.
我不明白
I don't get it.
杀了艾比让网络杀手进入到公众视野
Killing Abby put the Net Slayer onto the big stage.
嘲讽警察又让他受到瞩目
Taunting the police about it just turned on the klieg lights.
可现在为什么要选择这个没名气的呢
Why target a no-name like her?
或许他是想告诉大家没人是安全的
Maybe he's trying to send a message that no one's safe,
无论是网络名人还是无名的德国美食博主
Not Web celebs or obscure German-food bloggers.
这个名单得加上艺术家了
Well, you better add artists to that list, as well.
托瑞又确认了一副图片
Tory just I.D.'d another one of the images.
是Snappamatic上的吗
Is it from Snappamatic?
是的  是一个叫丹尼尔·里克的画家
Yeah, from the feed of a painter named Daniel Leek.
是从他照的一副画上取的
The image is from a photo he took of one of his pieces.
看  这个有效期
See, the, expiration date
是在这个奶盒上顶部的
is cropped from the top of this milk carton.
不过里克很少在Snappamatic上发图片
But Leek's pretty low on the Snappamatic totem pole.
他只有大约2000个粉丝
He only has about 2,000 followers.
真逊  我博客的粉丝都比他多
Heck, my blog has more than that.
你还有博客
You have a blog?
是的  是的  "莱恩报道"
Yeah, yeah. The -- the -- "The Ryan Report."
一个凶案组警探的沉思
It's the musings of a homicide detective.
你没看过
You haven't read it.
我没...我...莱恩报道
I don't... I..., The Ryan Report!
我只是...我以为...因为...
Yeah, I just... I... I thought, because I didn't...
先不管里克的粉丝数
Well, in spite of Leek's following,
把他带来再说吧
let's try to get him in.
这个有点难度
Well, that's going to be difficult.
他正在西雅图出席艺术节开幕式
He's at an art opening in Seattle.
他不住在纽约
He doesn't live in New York.
他在西雅图的话  怎么会成受害者
If he's in Seattle, how is he a possible victim?
他不是
He's not.
腐烂的水果  有效期
Rotten fruit, expiration date.
那幅画叫什么
What's the name of that painting?
好像是《变质》
"Spoiled," I think.
我知道这些线索是什么意思了
I know what the clues mean.
变质牛奶上的有效期  加上
Expiration date on spoiled milk plus...
烤香肠  等于
grilled bratwurst equals
被宠坏的小孩
spoiled brats.
这就是含义  你们明白了吗
That's the message. You getting it?
这就是这些图片的含义  指引我们...
That's what the images mean, leading us to...?
不是吧
Seriously?
除了我以外  你们都不看网上的杂志吗
Anyone here besides me a consumer of vapid online magazines?
不看
No.
被宠坏的小孩
Spoiled brats,
就像《Snappamatic上被宠坏的小孩》中写的
as in "The spoiled brats of Snappamatic."
是两周前的一篇专题文章
Feature article from two weeks ago.
是关于富二代们
It's all about rich kids who post pictures
在Snappamatic上发布奢侈生活的照片
of their extravagant lifestyles on Snappamatic.
这就是破案的关键
That's the key to solving the case.
我猜  凶手是给我们一些图片线索
The killer has given us a pictogram, as I predicted,
让我们找到这篇文章
pointing us to that article.
可能吧  那第三张图片呢
Yeah, maybe, but what about the third image?
-那副拼贴画   -就是它
- The collage? - This is it.
就是这张照片
This is the photo.
这些是塔蒂亚娜·费舍尔身体的部分
Those are Tatiana Fisher's body parts
取自她跟男朋友凯姆·马格尼一起照的照片
from this photo that she took with her boyfriend, Cam Magani.
他发在Snappamatic上的
He posted it on his Snappamatic feed.
被宠坏的小孩  塔蒂亚娜
Spoiled brat Tatiana.
她的粉丝数超过一百万
She has over a million followers.
杀了她会让凶手的名气大增
Going after her would raise the killer's infamy to new heights.
她是下个受害者
She's the next victim.
塔蒂亚娜·费舍尔
Tatiana Fisher.
纽约警局
NYPD.
我们一直在找你和凯姆·马格尼
We've been trying to get ahold of you and Cam Magani.
我们有理由相信
We have reason to believe
你可能是网络杀手的下个目标
that you might be the Net Slayer's next target.
太扯了  他不敢的
That's insane. He wouldn't dare.
可能吧  但我们要带你回警局
W-well, maybe not, but we need to take you back to the precinct.
我不会跟你走的
I'm not going anywhere with you.
我要去火烧岛参加派对  所以...
I have a party on Fire Island, so...
女士  你有可能处境危险
Ma'am, this is a potentially dangerous situation.
你刚才是叫我"女士"吗
Did you just call me "Ma'am"?
我简单说吧  好吧
Look, I'll make it simple for you, okay?
你们能强迫我跟你们走吗  能还是不能
Can you force me to go with you, yes or no?
不能
No.
那就行了  再见
Well, then. Bye-bye.
等一下  费舍尔小姐
Wait, Miss Fisher.
费舍尔小姐  拜托就给我们
Miss Fisher, please, just give us --
天哪  凯姆
Oh, my God, Cam!
今天一位蹲点社交媒体的连环杀手
The Internet is abuzz today
引起了网络上的广泛讨论
with news of a serial killer stalking social media.
在线图片分享应用Snappamatic的发言人
Representatives of Snappamatic,
发表声明
the online photo-sharing app, have released a statement
透露他们正在配合当局进行调查
saying that they are cooperating with authorities.
社会名流凯姆·马格尼被谋杀
Socialite Cam Magani's body was found murdered
其尸体发现于我身后的这辆汽车之中
in the vehicle you see behind me.
马格尼有可能是"网络杀手"
Magani may be the latest victim of Net Slayer,
这个神秘网络人物的最新受害者
the mysterious online figure
此人承认杀害艾比·史密斯
who claimed responsibility for the murder of Abby Smith,
并将她死后的照片发在网上
then posted gruesome images of her body.
整个城市和网络都笼罩在恐惧之中
With the city and Internet roiling with fear,
大家在疑问  连环杀手接下来会袭击谁
many are asking, "Who will this serial killer strike next,
此外当局何时能将他绳之以法
and when will authorities stop him?"
这家伙已经得到了他想要的东西  关注
This guy is getting exactly what he wanted -- attention.
这让他更加明目张胆
And it's making him bolder.
我们目前有什么进展
So where do we stand?
长官  凶手当时好像藏在凯姆车的后座
Sir, it looks like the killer hid in the backseat of Cam's car,
等着他进去  然后将他的喉咙割断
waited for him to get in, and then slit his throat.
他是怎么进去的
How did he get in the car?
我们还不确定
Well, we're not sure,
但鉴证组在门锁处找到了些塑料碎片
but C.S.U. found plastic fragments inside the door lock.
有可能是撬锁的工具
Might be from a lock pick.
到目前为止还没有收集到指纹和DNA
So far, there's no prints or DNA,
能确定的就只有凶手是右撇子
and all we know for sure is that the killer was right-handed.
为此我们付出的代价太大了
And we paid too high a cost for that knowledge.
警探  在我们遇到下一位被害人之前
Detective, bring me some good news
给我点好消息
before we lose another one.
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
不禁在想要是能早点想明白就好了
Can't help but think if only I'd figured it out sooner,
可能他现在还活着
maybe he'd still be alive.
就算那样也没有用
It wouldn't have mattered.
这游戏从一开始就不公平
The game was rigged from the start.
我们没有机会
We never had a chance.
凶手只是想让我们觉得自己有而已
The killer just wanted us to think we did.
现在网络杀手将会被更多人知道
And now the Net Slayer is gonna gain more notoriety
也会有更多的关注
and more flowers.
他已经做到了
He already has.
目前他已有五十多万的粉丝
He's at over half a million so far,
并且每分钟就增加了好几千
adding thousands more by the minute.
贝克特警探  又更新了两张照片
Detective Beckett, two more pictures just came in.
这次有些不同
Something different this time.
这个是先上传的
This one was uploaded first.
死亡证明  我觉得可以这么说
Proof of death, I guess you'd call it.
然后他发了这张
Then he sent this one.
卡塞尔  是我们在最初犯罪现场的照片
Castle, it's us before the first crime scene.
纽约警局在调查这次案件
"NYPS is on the case."
纽约人民  觉得安全吗  你们不该这么想
"Feel safe, New York? You shouldn't.
事情还没完
I'm not done."
从一开始他就在监视我们
He's been watching us from the beginning.
自始至终他都先我们一步
This guy has been ahead of us the whole time.
贝克特警探  说句话方便吗
Detective Beckett, a word?
纽约警察总局也看了照片  他们找到我
1pp saw that picture, too, and they called me,
他们担心你在此次案件中的表现
concerned about your commitment to this case.
长官  他们看到的太片面了
Sir, they're taking that photo out of context.
事实如何并不重要  凯特
The truth doesn't matter, Kate.
现在这已经是公关的问题了
It's a public-relations problem now.
凶手已经把你变成了
The killer just turned you into the poster child
这些谋杀案未能解决的负面形象
for these murders not being solved.
所以呢
So...what?
他们要把我撤出这个案子吗
They want to take me off the case?
我跟他们说不能
I told them no.
我不会让嫌疑犯通过控制舆论
I won't let our suspect sabotage this investigation
妨碍此次调查
by manipulating the narrative.
所以  回家吧  理清思路
So, go home, clear your head.
回到这里把他拿下
You get back here and you take his ass down.
这就是为什么我痛恨社交媒体
This is why I hate social media.
一旦发生些什么  事情就无法控制
Once something is out there, you have no control.
人们可以随意的将一些私人的瞬间
People can take a private moment
编造出事情的来龙去脉
and create their own context.
我是说  我们那时根本还没开始调查
I mean, we weren't even investigating the murder yet,
他们让我们看上去就像坏警察一样
and they made us look like we were bad cops.
更糟糕的是  好像我们不在乎
Or worse, like we didn't care.
没事的  贝克特
Come on, Beckett.
网络就是这样
It's the Internet.
没人会拿那张照片当真
No one's gonna take that picture seriously.
纽约警察总局就当真了
1pp did.
听着  事情很快就会平息的  好吗
Look, it's gonna blow over, okay?
每分钟都有无数的信息发布出来
With millions of items being posted every minute,
这只是网络连续体当中的一个小点
this is but a blip on the net continuum.
你知道匿名的问题在哪吗
You know the problem with anonymity?
毫无责任可言
There is no accountability.
这允许了那些胆小怕事的人成为恶霸
It empowers cowards to become bullies,
就像这家伙一样
just like this guy.
你知道吗
You know what?
大多数恃强凌弱的人最开始自己是受害者
Most bullies started out as victims themselves.
也许这人现在在网络上肆意攻击
Maybe this guy's lashing out on the Internet
是因为他之前受到过这样的凌辱
because it was used against him.
他曾经是网络犯罪的受害者
He was a victim of cyber crime.
比尔·加瑞特曾是网络警察
And Bill Garrett was a cyber cop.
凶手陷害他绝对不是巧合
It can't be a coincidence that the killer targeted him.
我们一直在找加瑞特抓起来的那些人
We've been looking at people Garrett put away...
我们应该去查一查那些案子里的受害者
When we should have been looking at victims of his cyber cases.
好的  我会联系加瑞特
Okay, I'll get a hold of Garrett.
我会让他查一下旧档案
I'll have him look into his old case files.
凶手肯定就在其中的某个地方
Our killer's got to be in there somewhere.
但是他到底是怎么潜入加瑞特的商店
Still, how did he get into Garrett's shop
来伪造证据  还有怎么进到凯姆的车里
to plant the evidence, or Cam's car?
我来告诉你怎么做到的  用一把钥匙
I'll tell you how -- with a key.
一把他做的钥匙
A key that he made.
3D打印机
3-D printer.
还记得我们在凯姆劳斯莱斯的
Remember the fragments that we found
锁孔里发现的碎屑么
in the lock of Cam's Rolls-Royce?
成分是聚乳酸
Well, they're PLA --
是一种用于3D打印的生物塑料
It's a bioplastic used in 3D printing.
鉴证组在艾比公寓的钥匙孔里
CSU found PLA in the locks at Abby's apartment,
和加瑞特店里的锁孔也发现了聚乳酸
as well as Garrett's shop.
凶手没有原件是怎么把钥匙配出来的
How could the killer make a copy of the key without the original?
配钥匙只要一张照片就够了
Turns out, all you need is a picture.
凯姆刚买到劳斯莱斯的时候
When Cam bought the Rolls,
他在网上晒照片炫耀来着
he bragged about it by posting a photo of the key
任何人都可以由此将钥匙模型数字化
that anyone could then digitize.
正如凶手所为
So, just as the killer did,
我把钥匙模型上传给打印机
I uploaded the photo to the printer and...
瞧瞧看
...voila!
真厉害
Outstanding.
与其说"真厉害"不如说"真可怕"
If by "Outstanding" you mean "Horrifying."
凶手拍了一张钥匙的照片
The killer snapped a photo of this key
然后用3D打印配了一把出来
and then made a 3D duplicate of it.
欢迎来到未来
Welcome to the future.
我还是想弄一台这机器
Still, I got to get one of these.
有什么办法能知道凶手是哪里买的打印机
Is there any way of finding out where the killer got his?
我们正在查
Well, we're checking.
不过除了实体店还有网上卖家
But between brick-and-mortar and online stores,
有上百个要查
we got hundreds of vendors.
这倒是解释了他怎么弄到凯姆的钥匙的
Well, this explains how he got Cam's key,
却没法说明加瑞特和艾比的情况
but not Garrett and Abby's.
艾比从来没传过有她钥匙的照片
Uh, Abby never posted photos of her keys.
她也很小心  从来不把钥匙随处乱丢
And she was careful. It's not like she left them lying around.
她有没有让人代停车过
Did she ever valet park her car?
没有  除了要出城她都很少开车的
No, she didn't even drive it except to get out of the city.
她的朋友里会有她家钥匙的吗
Any of her friends have keys to her place?
没有
No.
她就从来没让人在她家借宿过
She never let anybody crash there?
等等...
Actually...
艾比曾在旅游网站上出租过她的公寓
Abby used to rent out her apartment online through a travel site.
那些租客们  又是怎么拿到钥匙的
The people who stayed -- how'd they get her keys?
她就把钥匙放在门廊前的一块砖头下面
She'd leave them under a loose brick on her stoop.
我一直在查那些租过艾比公寓的人
So, I've been running the people that rented Abby's apartment.
为什么会有人让陌生人住他们家
Why would anyone let complete strangers stay in their place?
赚点外快
Extra money.
这事之后  我想我是不会再这么干了
After this, I don't think I'll be doing it anymore.
大部分租客都没问题
So, all the renters checked out,
除了有一位  预订之后就没有出现过
except for one guy who booked and never showed up.
这是来自艾比公寓对面的自动取款机
This is from an ATM across from Abby's apartment
就在那人本该入住的那天
on the day he was supposed to stay there.
那人其实来过  仔细看
Turns out a guy did show up. Check this out.
他给钥匙拍了张照片
He took a picture of her key.
他就是网络杀手  肯定是
It's the net slayer. It's got to be.
拍摄距离太远像素过低我没法放大
It's too far away and too low-res to blow up,
但仔细看  等他走过
but watch this as he walks away.
就这儿
There.
这下可以看清脸了
And now we have a face.
这人的身份调查进行得怎么样了
Okay. Where are we on finding this man?
我们正在分发他的照片
We're distributing his picture.
目前为止  尚未有受害人的家属
So far, none of the victims' families
或者邻居认出他来
or neighbors recognize him.
长官  我想把他的照片公布到媒体
Sir, I'd like to release his photo to the press
和社交网站
and social media.
这样我们就能转被动为主动
Let's turn the tables on this guy.
他一直在藏着
He's trying to hide it,
肯定有人能认出他来
but someone out there's gonna recognize his face.
你说的没错  那个人就是我
You're right, and that someone is me.
这位警官给我看他照片的时候
I was going over his case files
我正好在查看他的案件资料
when the officer showed me his photo.
他是谁
Who is he?
他叫安当·连恩
His name's Adam Lane.
你曾逮捕过他
You arrested him?
我认识他的时候他可不是罪犯
He wasn't a criminal when we met.
他是受害者
He was a victim.
那你知道他现在在哪里吗
And do you have any idea where he is now?
我已经有六年没有听到过他的消息了
I haven't seen or heard from Lane in six years.
他戴着的假胡子
Took me a minute to recognize him
让我花了好一会儿才认出他来
with that fake beard he's wearing.
好的
Okay.
我去准备把安当·连恩的姓名
I'll get ready to release Adam Lane's name
和照片发布给媒体
and picture to the media.
找不到连恩的当前住址
There's no current address for Lane.
继续找
Try to find one.
联系他的家人和任何可能认识他的人
Reach out to his family and anyone else that knows him.
与此同时
In the meantime,
你得把你知道任何有关安当·连恩的信息告诉我们
you need to tell us everything you know about Adam Lane.
当时连恩还是个高中生
Lane was in high school back then.
那是个网络欺凌案件
It was a cyber-bullying case.
是谁欺负他的
Who was bullying him?
他当时正在洗澡  一个叫蒂姆·威瑟斯彭的
He was taking a shower when this meathead football player,
白痴橄榄球运动员偷了他的衣服
Tim Witherspoon, stole his clothes.
类似的事情以前一直发生在连恩的身上
Now, this has happened to Lane his whole life,
不过这次  他被惹毛了
but this time, he went ballistic.
他就这样  一丝不挂
There he was, buck naked,
在更衣室里冲着威瑟斯彭大喊大叫
screaming at Witherspoon in a locker room.
我猜马上就是网络欺凌的部分了
I think I know where the cyber part comes in.
没错  威瑟斯彭偷偷录像了
Yeah, Witherspoon secretly recorded it
还把视频放到他的Myspace页面
and posted it on his Myspace page.
这回他被公开羞辱了
So he was publicly humiliated.
是的  不过不仅仅是羞辱
Yeah, but it wasn't just humiliation.
视频公开之后  所有的人都嘲笑他
After the video, the kids turned on him.
他的邮箱里堆满了他们发来的恶意邮件
They inundated him with these awful, hateful e-mails,
根本没有人被追究责任
and no one was held accountable.
为什么没有
Why not?
当时的网络欺凌法案还没健全
The cyber-bullying laws at the time were weak.
我让他们把视频撤下来了
I got them to take the video down,
但我没法说服检察官起诉他们
but I couldn't convince the D.A. to press charges.
我应该逼得更紧一些
I should've tried harder.
连恩后来怎样了
What happened to Lane?
每个人都会有崩溃的时候  对吧
Everyone has their breaking point, right?
退学  远离公众视野
Quit school, withdrew from life.
这件事毁了他
It ruined him.
他现在要通过追杀媒体上
And now he's getting revenge
有名气的孩子借以实施报复
by going after the popular kids on social media.
把我作为目标是因为我没有保护他
And targeting me because I didn't protect him.
不只是你  我们都是
Not just you -- all of us.
他有什么朋友吗
Did he have any friends?
有没有什么他喜欢去的地方
Was there anywhere he liked to hang out?
没有  他是个独来独往的电脑极客
Nah, he was a loner. Computer geek.
他几乎没什么朋友
He didn't have any friends.
我就只知道这些了
That's pretty much all I know.
没追踪到安当·连恩
Having no luck tracking down Adam Lane.
就好像他人间蒸发了一样
It's like he went off the grid.
没有纳税申报单  没有驾照  没有工作
No tax returns, no driver's license, no job,
除了三年前在殡仪馆工作过
except for a stint at a funeral home three years ago.
他一定是那时学会解剖的
That must be how he knows about anatomy.
他的父母呢
What about his parents?
父亲一直不在身边
Uh, father wasn't in the picture.
母亲一年前去世了
Mother died about a year ago.
听这个
Hey, get this --
我查到了蒂姆·威瑟斯彭  欺负连恩的那个人
I ran down Tim Witherspoon, Lane's bully.
原来他已经死了
turns out he's dead.
至今未破的谋杀案
Unsolved homicide.
十个月前他被刺死在自己的公寓里
He was stabbed in his apartment 10 months ago.
那正好也是连恩母亲死的时候
That's right after Lane's mother died.
也许这件事激发了他的复仇欲望
Maybe that's what triggered him.
所以他杀了威瑟斯彭  为自己报了仇
So, he murdered Witherspoon, took his revenge,
但这还不能满足他
but that wasn't enough for him.
连恩和他母亲住在哪里
Where did Lane and his mom live?
她死后  他卖掉了公寓
Well, the apartment sold when she died,
他们以前住在东部第五大道
but they lived on avenue at east 5th.
那是下东区
That's the lower east side.
自从我们放出连恩的照片
Ever since we released Lane's photo,
收到很多线报说他在那附近出现
we've had multiple tips that he'd been seen in that area.
像连恩这样的反社会青年无法融入社会
Anti-social kid like Lane who's never made his way in the world
他一定还会待在自己熟悉的地方
is gonna stay with what's familiar.
下东区是他唯一熟悉的地方
Lower east side's the only neighborhood he's ever known.
谁买下了他母亲的房子
Who bought his mother's place?
一对年老的俄罗斯夫妇
Uh... old Russian couple.
但地下室被租出去了
But the basement is a rental unit.
谁想赌一下连恩依旧住在那里
Who wants to bet Lane's still living there?
安当·连恩  你因谋杀罪被捕
Adam Lane, you're under arrest for murder.
你笑什么
What's so funny?
你会知道的
You'll see.
-出问题了  -什么问题
- We got a problem. - What's the problem?
我们已经扣押安当·连恩了
We got Adam Lane in custody.
他也扣押别人了
Well, he's got people in custody, too.
网络杀手主页上显示的
It just showed up on the Net Slayer feed.
什么人
What people?
Snappamatic的奥伦和肯特·维尔德
Oren and Kent Wilder from Snappamatic.
他们将成为下一组受害人
They're about to be his next victims.
"点赞否则我就会死"
"Like me or I die."
全凭人气投票
It's a popularity contest.
肯特要输了
And Kent is losing.
他们的照片每五分钟更新一次
These guys' photos update every five seconds,
还有他们的投票数
along with their votes.
他们都被连接上电引线
They're both attached to electrical leads.
那端的电源
Which probably lead to a power supply
应该是被电脑所控制
controlled by a computer.
倒数计时是一小时
That countdown started at one hour.
一旦时间归零
Once it reaches zero...
票数低的那个兄弟
Whichever brother has the least votes
心脏就要停跳了
gets his heart stopped.
或者都会死
Or they both do.
这是对社交媒体的终极进攻
It's the ultimate attack on social media.
还有我们
And us.
他们想让我们无能为力
He wants us to feel powerless.
尽管他已经被收押  可他们依然会死
Those guys are gonna die even though he's in custody.
如果我们先找到他们就不会死
Not if we get to them first.
在37分钟内吗
In 37 minutes?
怎么才能做到
How are we gonna do that?
他们都在油布前面
They're in front of tarps.
没有背景可供追查
There's no background detail.
他们可能在任何地方
These guys could be anywhere.
很可能是在两个不同的地方
Maybe even in separate places.
去Snappamatic办公室
Go to the Snappamatic offices.
也许他们能帮我们追踪到照片的来源
Maybe they'll help us track down the source of these photos
现在肯特和奥伦命悬一线
now that Kent and Oren's lives are at stake.
你准备怎么做
What are you gonna do?
我要让安当·连恩开口
I'm gonna make Adam Lane talk.
谁的票数高  奥伦还是肯特
So, who's ahead, Oren or Kent?
不仅是他们没有时间了  亚当
Time isn't just running out for them, Adam.
你也一样
It's running out for you, as well.
你就要失去
Your one and only window of opportunity
仅存的供认机会了
is about to close.
无可奉告
Got nothing to say.
我跟你说实话
Look, I'm not gonna lie to you.
你会进监狱的
You are going to prison.
但如果你告诉我们肯特和奥伦在哪里
But if you tell me where Kent and Oren are,
你还依然可以选择什么样的监狱
then you can still control what kind of prison.
那句话怎么说来着
What's the expression?
三顿热饭一张小床
Three hots and a cot?
我可以接受
Works for me.
如果你被送到重刑狱间
Yeah, well, you're not gonna be saying that
就不会这样说了
if you get sent to the supermax unit,
那里关押的都是最危险最暴力的犯人
where we put our most dangerous and violent inmates.
你的余生都会在那里渡过
You'll be on lockdown there 24/7 for the rest of your life.
不会比高中更惨的
Can't be any worse than high school.
是吗
Really?
你以为那时候你被欺负了吗
And you think that you were bullied?
在监狱里所遭受的待遇
Well, prison is going to take you places
是你现在无法想象的
that you can't imagine.
像你这样的年轻又听话的小伙
Guy like you, young, teachable.
没关系
Doesn't matter.
我已经得到我想要的了
I already have what I want.
你认为你得到什么了
And what do you think you have?
千古留名
A legacy.
互联网是永存的
The internet is permanent.
网络杀手将永垂不朽
The net slayer will live forever.
人们提起我就像是提起
I'll be mentioned in the same breath
曼森和十二宫杀手一样[均为变态连环杀手]
as Manson and the Zodiac.
而且
And...
如果我在被拘留期间
if I commit a murder while in police custody,
坐在你眼前
while looking you in the eye,
还杀了个人  那我就比他们还厉害
I could argue I did them one better.
你们无法阻止我
There's nothing you can do to stop me.
安当  你需要帮助
Adam, you need help.
你这是种病态
You're sick.
-让我帮你  -我是病态
- Let me get you - I'm sick?
我又没逼任何人关注我
Nobody had to follow me.
也没逼任何人给肯特或者奥伦投票
No one has to vote for Kent or Oren.
但是他们不能自已
But they can't help themselves.
他们想参与其中
They -- they want to be a part of it.
他们非看不可  所以病态的到底是谁
They have to watch. So...who is really sick?
他不是一直这样的
He wasn't always like that.
如果我可以回到过去重新来过的话
If I could go back and do it over again...
他变成这样不是你的错
You didn't make him this way.
可我也没能阻止事态的发展
Yeah, but I didn't stop it.
现在我也无法救那俩人的命
And now I can't stop these two guys from dying.
能让他开口的人非贝克特警探莫属
If anyone can break him, it's Detective Beckett.
而且Snappamatic或许也能帮到我们
And there's still a chance Snappamatic can help us.
进展如何
How we doing?
编码又不是按一下钮就行了
Coding's not like flipping a switch.
要时间的
It takes a little while.
我们没时间了  伊万
We don't have a while, Evan.
我们还有十五分钟的时间
We have...15 minutes to find these guys.
我已经尽快了
I'm going as fast as I can.
肯特在研究一个用来解锁
Kent was working on a software patch
隐私条款的软件补丁
that would disable the program's privacy protocols.
如果我们解锁了隐私条款
And if we disable the protocols,
就能追踪这些照片的来源了吗
we can track where these photos are coming from?
是的
Yes.
理论上是的
I mean, in theory.
问题是  我们从来没试过
The thing is, we've never done it before.
我不知道会不会成功
I don't know if it'll work.
我们没有找到绑架的目击者
Our canvass didn't turn up a single witness to the abduction.
我们毫无进展
We're nowhere, bro.
但愿你这边有进展
Tell me you got something.
就快有结果了
About to find out.
好了  开始吧
Okay, let's do this.
发生什么事了
What happened?
系统崩溃了  我们被锁住了
System crash. We're locked out.
重启啊
Well, get it back up.
再过十五分钟这俩人就没命了
We got 15 minutes before these guys are dead.
重启要二十分钟
It takes 20 minutes to reboot.
发生什么事了
What just happened?
他们的尝试失败了  网站崩溃了
Whatever they were trying didn't go well. The site just crashed.
我们无法追踪奥伦和肯特的所在地
So there's no way to trace those feeds of Oren and Kent
而计时器将会继续倒计时
and the timer will just keep counting down
直到他们其中一人死掉为止
until one of them is dead?
现在一切都指望贝克特了
It's all up to Beckett now.
安当  只要回答一个问题
Adam, just answer one question,
也许就能救你的命
and it might save your life.
奥伦和肯特在哪
Where are Oren and Kent?
如果你们警察有能力的话  早就找到了
If you cops were capable of doing your jobs, you'd know.
回头看看
And, looking back,
也许这一切就都不会发生了
maybe none of this would have ever happened.
我知道在你身上发生的事很残忍
Look, a horrible thing was done to you.
但是多杀两个人也于事无补呀
But how is killing two more people going to fix that?
这能治愈你吗  不能
How is that gonna heal you? It won't.
可以
It will.
你难道没看出我已经赢了吗
Don't you see that I've already won?
这样吧
I'll tell you what --
承认我赢了  我就给你个提示
admit that I've won and I'll give you a hint.
我给你个机会找到肯特或奥伦
I'll give you a chance to find Kent or Oren before...
好吧
Fine.
你赢了
You won.
给我提示吧
Now give me the hint.
我改变主意了
Changed my mind.
还剩七分钟
Seven minutes left.
她必须做点什么  逼他开口
She's got to make a move, shake him up somehow.
她会的
She will.
网络杀手
Net Slayer.
真能引起共鸣啊
That's evocative.
我能理解你为什么会选这么个名字
I could -- I could see how you would pick that.
我能想象到一个身穿黑色连帽衫
I picture a-a hooded figure in all black,
又高又壮的人  没准还拿着个斧子
tall, muscular, maybe carrying an ax.
但是你知道我想象不到什么吗  安当
But you know what I don't picture, Adam?
任何人都想像不到的东西
What nobody pictures?
你
You.
你以为你赢了吗
You think that you won?
你没有  别人都赢了
You haven't. Everyone else has.
什么意思  什么叫别人都赢了
What do you mean, "Everyone else"?
所有那些欺负过你的人
Everyone who ever bullied you,
伤害过你  轻视过你的人
who ever hurt you, belittled you,
还有那些认为你软弱无能渺小的人
Who thought that you were weak and worthless and small.
你知道吗  安当
And you know what, Adam?
他们是对的
They were right.
不  不是
No, they weren't.
我才不是那种人呢
I am not any of those things.
你比那还要糟
You're all of them and worse.
是他们把我变成现在这样的
I am what people made me.
你天生如此  或是你母亲把你造就成这样的
You were born this way, or your mommy made you.
但是蒂姆·威瑟斯彭和学校里其他的孩子
But Tim Witherspoon and the rest of the kids at school,
他们并没有毁了你
they didn't break you.
你早就是这样了
You were already broken.
他们只是感受到你的本质
They only sensed what you were
和你即将成为的样子
and what you were about to become.
你知道吗
So you know what?
从某种角度来讲  他们的欺凌还不够
In a way, their bullying wasn't enough.
你怎么能说这种话
How can you say that to me?
我是受害者
I'm the victim here.
你永远是受害者
And you're always gonna be a victim.
你以为躲在一个用户名后
You think that hiding behind a username
肆意杀人就能改变一切吗
and killing is going to change that?
你不会得到尊敬
That won't get you respect.
你永远都是
You're always gonna be
那个可悲的失败者
the same pathetic loser that you were!
我不是失败者
I'm not a loser!
当你绑架肯特和奥伦时
And when you abducted Kent and Oren,
他们肯定望向彼此  在想
I bet the two of them looked at each other and thought,
我们被恶搞了吗
"Are we being punk'd here?"
相信我  他们没有
Believe me, they didn't.
-他们以为这是玩笑  -他们很害怕
- They think it's a joke. - They're afraid.
他们吓坏了
They're -- they're terrified.
他们现在在嘲笑你
They're sharing a laugh right now about you.
没有
They are not laughing!
她诱他说出他们在一起
She just got him to say that they're together.
他们在笑
Oh, they're laughing.
正开心地笑着
They're laughing right now.
笑不了多久了
Well, not for long.
时间归零
That clock will hit zero,
他们吸入最后一口污浊的空气时
and their screams will echo off the tiled walls
他们的尖叫会在壁砖墙间回荡
as they take in their last breath of stale air.
之后他们都会被电死
And then they'll both fry.
壁砖墙和污浊的空气
Tiled walls and stale air?
他当时是这么描述学校更衣室的
That was how he talked about the locker room at his school.
威瑟斯彭在那里拍了录像
Where Witherspoon put him on video.
他这是要在开始地方结束一切
He's bringing this thing full circle.
哪个高中
What was the name of that high school?
哈丁高中  但他们校园搬走了
Harding High, but they moved to a new campus.
原来的大楼封掉了
The original building is shut down.
贝克特
Beckett!
哈维  电线
Javi, the wires!
还好吗
You okay?
Okay?
感谢你们让我参与此案
I just wanted to say thanks for letting me pitch in.
你开玩笑吗  没有你我们破不了案的
Are you kidding me? We couldn't have done this without you.
奥伦和肯特活下来也都是因为你
Yeah, Oren and Kent are alive because of your help.
能破案总是很棒的
Well, it's always good to get a win.
再会
Well, see ya around.
See ya around.
拜
See ya.
以前这种事是有个末了的
You know, there used to be some finality to all of this.
照张照片  扔进盒子
You took a photo, dump it in the box,
再也不会看到那张脸
and you never see that face again.
再也不是了
Not anymore.
安当·连恩每天晚上都会出现在新闻上
Yeah, Adam Lane is gonna be on the news every night,
在网上就持续数周  数月
be on the web for weeks -- months.
甚至数年
Geez, years.
反讽的是  抓住了他
Ironic that by catching him,
我们给了他最想要的  更多的粉丝
we're giving him exactly what he wanted -- more followers.
这个案子之后  我要断会网
Well, after this case, I think I'm ready to unplug,
远离网络一段时间
stay off the internet for a while.
是的  但在那之前
Yes, but before you do,
我们还有最后一件网络事宜
We have one last piece of internet business.
进来  伙计们
Come in, you guys. Come in.
-这边  -好
- Right this way. Right this way. - Okay.
你先走
After you.
我的发行商刚刚把链接给我
All right, my publisher just sent me the link
《狂怒希特》的网络广告
for the webmercial for "Raging Heat."
等待欣赏杰作吧  三  二  一
Prepare for greatness in three, two, one.
我是理查  嘴里有口香糖
Hi. I'm Richar-- I've got gum.
我把口香糖吐了
I'm gonna put my gum out.
*我是理查德·卡塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Richard Castle*
*我是卡查德·理塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Crichard Ratchel*
*我是理查德·卡塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Richard Castle*
*我是卡查德·理塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Crichard Ratchel*
*我是理查德·卡塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Richard Castle*
*令人后背发凉  曲折迷离的小说*
*For a spine-tingling, bone-chilling adventure*
*《狂怒希特》*
*"Raging Heat"*
*令人后背发凉  曲折迷离的小说*
*For a spine-tingling, bone-chilling adventure*
*《狂怒希特》*
*"Raging Heat"*
*令人后背发凉  曲折迷离的小说*
*For a spine-tingling, bone-chilling adventure*
*《狂怒希特》*
*"Raging Heat"*
*令人*
*For a sp--*
这不是冒险  这是惊悚小说
It's not an adventure. It's a thriller.
今天就下载一本吧
Why don't you download your copy today?
*我是理查德·卡塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Richard Castle*
*我是卡查德·理塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Crichard Ratchel*
*我是理查德·卡塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Richard Castle*
*我是卡查德·理塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Crichard Ratchel*
*我是理查德·卡塞尔*
*Hi, I'm Richard Castle*
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell was that?
爸  已经有100万点击量了
Dad, you've gotten over a million hits.
有100万人看过了
A million people have seen that?
是的  已经是热门视频了  亲爱的
Yeah. Well, it's gone viral, darling.
这不是你想要的吗
Isn't that what you wanted?
-不是以这种方式  -别担心  卡塞尔
- Not like this. - Oh, don't worry, Castle.
会过去的
It'll blow over.
这只是网络连续体当中的一个小点
This is but a blip on the net continuum.
但是我们得再看一遍
But we so need to watch this one again.
嗨
Oh. Hi.